

MATTHEW LEWIS

HTML5

Game

Developer

About Me

Over the past 9 years I have had the pleasure to work full time on web apps for 5 major platforms and many HTML5 games and game frameworks.

I have worked for small and large companies both in-house and as part of outsourced development teams.

I shipped 3 freelance HTML5 game projects during 2020.

I also mentored on a fullstack web development course teaching React/ Express/PostgreSQL in 2020/21.

Contact

- > +44 7743675437
- > mattoubatou@gmail.com
- > Cornwall, UK
- **Linkedin**
- <u>Github</u>

Education

- > BA (hons) Illustration
 Arts University Bournemouth
 2009 2010
- > FdA Visual Communication
 Arts University Bournemouth
 2007 2009

Experience

Game Developer

Solo Game Dev | Personal | November 2022 - Present

CMAKE Batch-Scripts

- Game developing purely in C for the Playdate handheld console <u>play</u>.
 <u>date</u>
- Created engine features such as: animated sprites, tilemap loading and rendering, entity spawning/rendering management systems, combat system and efficient collision detection.
- Created custom exporters for Texture Packer, Tiled and Aseprite.
- All graphics, sound, music, game design.

HTML5 Game Developer

Gamebook | Contract | May 2022 - October 2022

JS React CSS Jira

Independently porting narrative mobile games to HTML5 matching all game animations and effects using only html (React) and css.

Confluence

Pivi 7S

- Developing UI to navigate story content while ensuring responsiveness.
- Managed tasks using Jira and created documentation and change logs in Confluence.

Senior HTML5 Game Developer

GAN | Full-time | March 2021 - March 2022

Typescript CSS React

- Independently developed and shipped an online slot game that contained individually spinning 3d symbols (instead of the classic reels spin animations) from start to finish.
- Developed initial prototype features for an in-house slot game building tool to eventually allow faster turnaround on front-end game

Fullstack Web Development Mentor

Thinkful | Contract | July 2020 - March 2021

JS CSS HTML React Express NodeJS PostgreSQL

Mentoring 5-10 students per week in a full stack program with PostgreSQL, Express, React and Node tech stack.

- Providing weekly online 1:1 support for students enrolled into Thinkful's full stack engineer programs.
- Ensuring students are understanding curriculum content and providing additional external resources where appropriate.
- Giving hands-on coding demos to help reinforce key concepts with JS,
 CSS, HTML, React (Class/Hooks/Context api), Express and PostgreSQL.

HTML5 Game Developer

Maclean Creative | Freelance | June 2020 - Sep 2020

Construct 3

Developed 2 HTML5 educational games using Construct 3 and Adobe Animate for both desktop and landscape devices.

- Developed 2 HTML5 educational games using Construct 3 and Adobe
 Animate for both desktop and landscape devices.
- Provided project planning using Trello including time estimates for every feature.
- Liased with artists to ensure game screens and UI elements where executed as designed.

Skills

































Software



















HTML5 Game Developer

Sandboxx Studio | Freelance | March 2020 - April 2020

Construct 3 **jQuery**

Vaccinator Quest game for the Gavi Vaccine Alliance.

- Provided HTML5 Game development services from early prototypes to finished features using Construct 3.
- Provided proof of concept game integrations with clients microsite and online petition pages.
- Provided consultation services during the complete life of the project around technical issues in delivering the final game builds that integrate with the clients microsite and petition pages.

Front End Developer

Headforwards (BoxIt) | Full-time | Jan 2020 - April 2020 React Redux SCSS Webpack BDD Jest Enzvme

SaaS React app that allows companies to scan and search physical documents with accompanying React Portal site to allow usage of other third party document scan and search services.

- Developed new features for existing React App (Class/Hooks Components/ Redux).
- Ejected CRA based app (prior to me joining the team) and refactored it pulling out reusable components into a core component library and created a second app that reused components in the new component
- Created POC of a user customisable dashboard (based on mocks from an external designer) to enable users to create bespoke spending/service usage reports.
- Wrote Unit tests for all React component functionality.
- Contributed to architectural decisions with Backend developers.

Front End Developer

Headforwards (NTT) | Full-time | October 2019 - Jan 2020 Redux SCSS Webpack TDD Jest **Enzyme Cypress** React dashboard-based Cloud Management Platform to allow large companies (Coca Cola, Disney, Sony, Nintendo and more) to monitor server usage on an international scale.

- Developed React components (Class/Hooks/Redux) for a dashboard management system.
- Wrote integration tests with Cypress and unit tests (TDD) with Jest, Mocha, Chai and Enzyme ensuring a target 80% code coverage.
- Responsible for app deployments to staging servers including manual testing to catch and report bugs before final deployment to production.
- Contributed to project task breakdowns and LOE estimations.

HTML5 Game Developer

Epic Industries Ltd | Full-time | Dec 2018 - Sep 2019 PixiJS Webpack Mocha **Typescript**

Award winning games for leading iGaming platforms.

- Helped to develop 5 iGaming games to work in all major browsers across PC and mobile using the PixiJS rendering library.
- Successfully combined Canvas and DOM rendering with SVG/SCSS to produce games with responsive cross-browser game UIs.
- Wrote unit tests to provide at least 90% code coverage.

Front End Developer

Headforwards (NTT) | Full-time | Apr 2017 - Dec 2018

Backbone Marionette React Redux Webpack TDD/BDD Mocha Chai Jest Enzyme

Enterprise services to allow large companies to manage servers in datacenters across the globe.

- Helped to build a front end application that connects multiple microservices into a single cohesive SPA. (Backbone, Marionette & React).
- Rebuilt a Backbone/Marionette app with React (Class/Functional components & Redux) as part of a small team, creating our requirements from old web app features and liasing with external Backend team to ensure smooth integration of new api's.
- Unit testing with Mocha, Chai, Jest and Enzyme ensuring a target 80% code coverage & integration testing with Cypress.

HTML5 Game & Web App Developer

EducationCity.com | Full-time | Jul 2014 - Apr 2017

JS SVG Canvas EaselJS Phaser PixiJS AngularJS MVC/

MVVM

Leading developer and publisher of primary school level online teaching resources used in over 75 countries.

- Developed 3 HTML5 casual games using EaselJS rendering library together with Adobe Animate.
- Created 5 HTML5 game frameworks and accompanying WYSIWIG game building tools to allow the continued release of educational content on desktops and mobile devices.
- Worked very closely with artists to ensure HTML5 games featured tv quality cartoon animations (SVG and Canvas).
- Developed over 10 Flash games using AS2/AS3 and XML for game settings and educational assets (copy text, audio, animations).
- Mobile ready HTML5 video player with the videojs library with accessibility features and subtitles for children's educational songs used in UK and Spanish primary schools.
- Gamified educational game portal with character animation rich interface and smooth 60fps animations throughout using PixiJS rendering library and Angular JS.
- Forms with secure authentication to sign up for new accounts and take subscription purchases.
- Backend (PHP, Lumen, Laravel, Liquibase) to Frontend (Angular 2) development of core site features to allow users to customise their UI.